Okay, what I'm going to show you here is
called async and await. And this is how
you can write asynchronous code that
looks so similar to synchronous code. I
think you'll really like it. Um, it
works on the same principle as promises.
So, we do still have to have a promise.
That promise will resolve or reject um
after something happens. Um, so in our
case, after a timeout is done, it will
resolve. So, after a set time, our code
will run. um or if you were working over
the network, which we're going to be
getting to in a couple of videos. Um
this could be as soon as you get a
response with the data. So, um here
we've got our function um that returns a
promise. If we want to use asynchronous,
if we want to use the keywords async and
await, they need to be inside of a
function that's asynchronous. So, we
need to write ourselves a function here.
So, the way we do this is well, I'm
going to show you with both function
methods. So you could say async function
um test and you could write your
function that way or if you like the
other way of defining functions I could
say const test 2 equals async
and then create my arrow function. So
that's that's the two ways you can
define it. Um I'm going to write it
here. But now that we are inside of an
asynchronous function, we can await
certain things to happen. So if I want
to wait a set amount of time before I
console.log something, I could say let
results equal
await
the wait function for 3,00 seconds. And
then right below it,
I'll console.log
the result.
So if you notice this is strikingly
similar. Do how you would write your
normal code. Um you said do something
and then on the next line do something
else. But this await keyword here is the
key thing. It says this entire function
will run after this is completed. So
we're going to wait for this to
complete. And you can let the rest of
your code run on as normal, but don't
move to this line until this line is
complete. So if we save this and we come
over and we reload the page. Oh, one
thing I always forget, you do need to
call your function after you've defined
it. So, right here, I'm going to call
test.
So, if we call it
3 seconds later, there's hello world.
And the great thing is, remember when I
told you last time that like, oh, well,
now you're going to have to chain your
thens together. If I want to wait 3
seconds and then wait another five after
that, I write it just like you would
expect. I'd say let result two equal
await wait
5 seconds and then console.log
result two.
So if you save this and you come over oh
actually it would be helpful if I grab
my timer. Let me grab my timer from
promise. So I've hidden this timer so
you didn't have to look at it. But let's
put it in.
We're on a sync so I'm going to add it
in. right here. And I'm gonna hide those
lines of code so you don't have to look
at them. But I have a function right
there that's going to be counting off
the seconds. So if we come over, waited
1 second, 2 second, 3 seconds, hello
world, 4 seconds, 5 seconds, 6 seconds,
7 seconds, 8 seconds, hello world, just
like we would expect. And so that's the
amazing thing about async and wait. You
can write your code almost the same as
you did before, but you just said wait
for that result to come back. And you
get all of the benefits of asynchronous
code, meaning my screen didn't freeze up
while I waited those 5 seconds, but you
get to write it as if it was normal code
where you just write line after line
exactly how you would expect it to
execute. And that is the power of async
and wait. And in fact um in the next
video I will show you um if we come to
this one I showed you callbacks then I
showed you how to chain vends together.
I'll show you how to do it with async
and away and I promise you the code
looks a lot less exciting but it's more
readable.